WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
(BELL RINGS)
Housekeeper used to be Mrs Hughes.
I don't know if she's still here.
Leave everything to me, m'lord.
See you upstairs. I won't be up
before the gong.
Can I help?
Stick it under my arm if you can.
You're an angel.
I don't know about that.
Do you know where Lord Gillingham's
room is? The maid will show you.
You've got the answer to everything.
I suspect you have too,
Mr Gillingham.
Was the train on time, Sir John?
It was all as efficient as you like.
(WOMAN LAUGHS)
Mrs Jefferson, how nice to see you!
Which one's Mr Sampson
and why have we asked him?
Ah well, I see him at White's every
now and then and he seemed keen to
come.
He's over there, talking to Mama.
Ah yes.
Who's the glamorous pirate?
Don't you recognise
Johnnie Gillingham's son?
Anthony Foyle?
Yes but he's Lord Gillingham now.
I haven't seen him
since his father's funeral.
I know, but I wrote afterwards
and he answered.
Well.
How nice of you to come.
It's good to be back at Downton.
Mary, you remember Anthony Foyle?
Sorry, Gillingham.
I remember
a very superior young man
who found three little girls
extremely tiresome to deal with.
I seem to be outnumbered
by your parents' old friends.
Don't worry. You and Papa are
going to get to know each other
this time. I promise.
You're the agent here now,
aren't you? Mary told me.
You must miss darling Sybil
so dreadfully.
Yes. Did you have a good journey?
I'm afraid Tom's
small talk is very small indeed.
Not everyone can be Oscar Wilde.
That's a relief.
Go up when you like. We'll gather
in the drawing room at eight.
Ten staying and only three
maids and two valets between them.
Not quite like before the war,
is it? Very little is.
They're mostly easy and the Duchess
of Yeovil's no trouble at all.
We don't know Mr Sampson
or Sir John Bullock
and we haven't seen
Lord Gillingham for a while.
Oh, Anna,
can you look in on Mrs Jefferson?
They're in the Chinese.
Of course.
Oh, Edna, Lady Raven might need
a helping hand. She's in Fontenoy.
She says she's used to having
no maid but I rather doubt it.
I'm not sure I've got time.
Make time!
Poor Lady Raven.
When you think of her life
ten years ago and now.
I'm told she has some dingy
little house north of the park.
It's a wonder they still ask her
to stay.
Well, perhaps her ladyship
does not wish
to cast away an old friend
because she lives north of the park.
I know, I know. But still, it's sad.
We never moved back after the war.
It was a hospital, you know.
And now?
It's a girls' school.
Hmm. But we're quite
comfortable in the Dower House.
Did you ever see it?
I remember having tea there
with your grandmother.
She gave me ice cream
and I got it all over my dress.
Nanny was furious.
That sounds like Grandmama.
She'd always say how children
should be spoiled.
She's gone now, so she'll never know
if I took her advice.
You have no children?
No.
No children, no wife.
I've come close a couple of times.
In fact, I'm close now.
What about you?
I have a son, George.
You know that Matthew...
Oh God, I'm... I'm sorry.
Of course I know.
I just wasn't thinking.
Please forgive me.
There's nothing to forgive.
I go this way and you're down there.
Oh, not those bowls, Ivy!
Chilled soup should be an exquisite
mouthful, not a bucket of slop!
I'll get the smaller ones.
How are the squabs doing?
Fine, Mrs Patmore.
What about the syllabubs?
The orange peel and brandy is in the
larder. I'll whip the cream during
the first course.
What about the savoury?
Mushrooms peeled and cut.
Butter's ready. I'll make
the toast when they eat the pudding.
Oh my God, the vegetables!
She'll bust a gut
if she keeps that up.
Have you settled him in,
Mr Gillingham?
I wish you could call me Green.
My real name.
Mr Carson wouldn't approve.
He believes in the old ways.
What do you believe in?
I believe in getting on
with my work.
All work and no play makes Jack
a dull boy and Jill a dull girl.
I should organise some games.
I'll organise you
if you don't watch out!
They finally got you
into white tie, I see.
More's the pity. I've never felt
more stupid in my life.
I was wondering why we've never
spoken since I came back.
I hope we can still be friends?
Of course. Of course we can.
But we can't have lunch again
at the pub in the village.
Braithwaite...
Edna.
I'm trying to walk
a tightrope here...
As long as you're not my enemy.
God, no.
I hope things turn out well for you.
I do, truly.
I gather the abbey is once more
to be a scene of great splendour.
Are you going up there
for any of it?
I'm supposed to go for dinner
on the last night. To hear Melba
sing.
Oh. I envy you.
But you don't sound very glad.
I don't want them to spend their
days in Stygian gloom, I really
don't.
They say life must go on
and of course it must.
But it seems disloyal to Matthew.
Not disloyal, exactly.
What does Lady Mary feel?
Oh, you know Mary.
She's always quite opaque.
I love Al Jolson, don't you?
I've got all his records.
Including April Showers?
Of course. I love it madly.
Are you ever in London?
I might be.
We're a little exposed up here
to sow barley as a winter crop.
The Duke always swore by it.
Did you know barley beer was
probably the first alcoholic drink?
It was developed by Neolithic man.
So we all owe him quite a debt.
Do we?
Oh, there's poor Lady Raven. I
really ought to go and talk to her.
Of course, Your Grace.
Don't call her Your Grace.
I thought it was correct.
For a servant,
or an official at a ceremony,
but in a social situation,
call her Duchess.
But why? I don't call you Countess.
Certainly not!
There's no logic in it.
Oh no,
if I were to search for logic,
I should not look for it
among the English upper class.
Thomas, get me a drink will you,
for God's sake. It's Barrow now,
sir. But yes, of course.
What about a hand at cards?
Why not?
I'll get them to set up a table
for you in the smoking room. Barrow?
Er, already done, m'lord.
Will you play, Lord Grantham?
I don't think so. Not tonight.
Do you ever play?
Well, I used to.
Tonight I'd rather be with you.
It's no trouble. We have plenty of
horses and Papa would be delighted.
Have you anything to ride in?
We packed it all in case.
Well, that settles it. I'll send
a message to the stables tonight.
Will you come out with me?
Actually I might. I haven't
been in the saddle for ages.
I'll be as stiff as a board
the next day.
Would anyone else
like to go riding tomorrow morning?
Sir John? Mr Sampson?
Must I?
(LAUGHTER)
Edith?
Do you ride?
Not if I don't have to.
I'm afraid you're stuck with me.
Why on earth are you doing that
at this ungodly hour?
Where are the girls?
I sent them to bed.
I thought I might get ahead
of myself. I might lay out what I
need for the breakfast.
All set for tomorrow?
I think so.
Where should we feed Dame Nellie
on Sunday? She can't eat in the
servants' hall.
And what about the pianist?
Well, he can join us
and she can have a tray in her room.
You don't think she should dine
with the house party?
An Australian singer?
Eating with her ladyship?
Never mind the Duchess!
No, I do not!
Mr Molesley?
Hello.
What are you doing? Mrs Patmore left
an order with Mr Bakewell. She said
it was urgent.
What's this, Mr Molesley?
Are you delivering for Bakewell's?
I'm just filling in.
Until something turns up.
You're a delivery boy? Now, now,
Daisy. There's no shame in hard
work.
You sit there, Mr Molesley,
and I'll fetch you some tea.
You played late. I hope you didn't
think me rude for going to bed.
No. Not a bit.
How was the game?
Sampson is a very skilled player.
Where were you last night?
Being thrashed by Sampson.
(LAUGHS) Poor you!
I hope that means
I can count on you tonight.
You can always count on me.
What are your plans for today?
I'll go to the wood,
look at the new planting.
Won't you help me
entertain our guests?
Just give me two hours off
and I'll do whatever you want.
We're going for a walk
after breakfast. Why don't you come?
I don't think so. I've got too much
to do, rounding this lot up.
Coffee?
Not yet, thank you.
I'm going to manage it somehow.
I've a feeling he's good at putting
off what he doesn't want to do.
He's not as calculated as that.
How little we know our own parents.
Apparently he took a fortune
off Sir John Bullock.
What about your employer? His
lordship's too clever. He got out
the game early.
That's not what I heard.
What were they playing?
Poker.
Of course it was poker.
You can't lose a fortune
playing snap. I could!
Mabel Lane Fox? So you've caught
the greatest heiress of the season.
She's very nice, in fact.
I'm sure.
Of course, everyone wants it,
on both sides, but we do get on.
You may be surprised to hear that a
match wanted by everyone can turn
out to be extremely happy.
Do you speak from experience?
Absolutely.
Matthew and I were flung at each
other's heads from the moment
he arrived.
If anything,
it rather slowed matters up.
But you were happy?
Wonderfully happy.
How lucky you are.
Am I?
You've known a great love.
Doesn't that enrich any life?
I'm not sure. Matthew changed me.
I loved him but he changed me.
If I were as tough as I was before
I met him, I bet I'd be happier now.
Maybe.
But we can't go back, can we?
Apparently not.
What will you do with that?
Cover it and dry it on the stove,
then put it into muslin bags.
Lady Gillingham's maid
buys it in packets.
Perhaps she's not a country girl.
Judging by you, she's the poorer
for that.
You've plenty of time for chatter.
You can blame me.
I'm afraid it's a failing of mine.
I do blame you.
(BELL RINGS)
What is the matter?
I don't know. There's something
about him that gets my goat.
He was just trying to be nice.
Carson. We're all going on a tour
of the gardens in ten minutes.
When we get back, it might
be nice to have some coffee.
Very well, m'lady.
Is everything under control?
It is.
It's exciting to think
of Nellie Melba singing at Downton.
I'm not sure about exciting.
It's certainly very expensive.
A house party can be so flat
if there's no special moment.
And it wouldn't be special enough
to watch the sun set by the lake?
Good morning, ladies.
Good morning.
What is it?
I can't get the lid off this.
Give it here.
I'll do it.
Stand back.
Let a real man handle it.
Come on.
I wonder
what happened to that real man?
See? Told you I was master here.
That'll teach you to show off!
I hurt myself, thank you!
You'll mend which is more than I can
say for that jar.
Daisy, Ivy, clear this mess up.
As I assume Mr Clever Clogs won't.
I'm getting quite fluent.
You're taking German lessons?
(LAUGHS) If I'm going to live there.
No, no. Of course.
I just can't get over the fact
you're doing all this to be with me.
Whatever it takes.
Michael was admiring the library.
It's marvellous.
Edith tells me
there's a Gutenberg Bible.
Yes. It's a shame our librarian,
Mr Pattinson, isn't here.
He's the only one
who knows where anything is.
If you'll excuse me? I must go
and sort out the wine for tonight.
He doesn't approve of me.
He doesn't know you.
Nor is he likely to.
Serve the Margaux at dinner and keep
the Haut-Brion for tomorrow.
No the '99, if we have enough.
I want to go out with a bang.
And you can choose the white.
Very good, m'lord.
Her ladyship has been kind enough
to invite the servants to hear
Dame Nellie tomorrow evening.
It's a rare opportunity for them.
She's very generous.
But I wondered, what are
we to do about the kitchen staff?
Why? Do you fear the corrupting
influence of opera? Not at all,
m'lord.
But before the war they wouldn't
usually have been included. I think
we must bend that far, Carson.
Modern times and all that.
As you wish, m'lord.
I've arranged for Dame Nellie's
accompanist to sleep with the male
servants.
I doubt he'd expect to sleep
with the female ones!
And Dame Nellie will have
dinner in her room. Very good.
Whatever you think.
How wonderful to see an estate
that's still all in one piece.
Don't speak too soon.
What do you mean?
Well, we have a big tax bill to pay.
Papa wants to sell land but
I'd like to see if we can avoid it.
The trouble is,
I can't get him to listen.
Shall I tell you what I'd do?
Please.
Make him agree for you to meet
the tax people
then bring back the best deal
they can offer.
In that way
you'll have a real case to argue.
We had a similar choice
when Father died.
In the end,
we let the house but kept the land.
Thank you.
It's nice to know one's not alone.
That others
are facing the same trials.
No.
You're not alone.
Argh! What's up?
I've jiggered my bloody wrist!
I'll have no swear words
in here, thank you very much.
Unless I'm doing the swearing.
What's going on?
Why aren't you upstairs?
Jimmy hurt his wrist.
He can't carry the tray.
What?
I'll do my best, Mr Carson.
Is something wrong?
Why are you down here?
Who's in the dining room?
I'm going back up.
I wondered what the delay was.
Oh no, that's no good.
Mr Barrow, you'll have to do it.
Mr Carson, must I remind you
that I am the under butler?
I don't care if you're the high
cockalorum. You're a footman
tonight.
Sorry, Mr Barrow.
MAN: It wasn't her husband,
it was a dog! (MEN LAUGH)
I'm getting up a game.
What about you, Gillingham?
I don't think so.
I'll join you if you like.
Is there a place for me?
Certainly.
Shall we meet in the smoking room
in ten minutes? Very good.
Be careful if I were you.
Sampson is a very sharp player.
I think I can look after myself.
It looks terribly heavy.
I'm playing cards with your father.
He'll have to talk to me if we're
at a card table.
I hope James isn't really hurt.
I don't think so, m'lady. Good.
We'll have to muddle
through tomorrow as well.
Don't worry about that, m'lady.
I have an idea.
You do realise we can sell land as
a capital gain and pay no tax on it
at all?
And end up with an estate
that can't support the house.
I doubt it will change my mind.
I'm glad you only doubt it.
I must be making some progress.
(MUSIC)
What's that?
Is there anyone who wants to dance?
I jolly well do. If it's with you.
I love dancing but these days
I haven't got a partner.
Tom? You're dressed for it.
Would you care to dance with me,
Duchess? I should love it.
I hate to pass up a chance
to hold you in my arms...
Why do you have to play?
Because I've said I will.
What about it?
I thought I'd keep Granny company.
Don't use me as an excuse. If you
don't want to dance, tell him.
Do you know Racing Demon? I've heard
of it but I've never played.
I'll teach you.
We'll bring in some of the others.
You need a pack of cards for every
player. We can manage that.
Anna, can you give me a hand with
this shirt? I've got shoes to clean.
Of course.
I'm very fond of Ireland.
Where did you grow up?
Bray, in County Wicklow.
Oh, I love Wicklow! Of course,
you must know the Powerscourts.
I know of Lord Powerscourt, yes.
Lady Powerscourt is my niece.
Have you met her?
I've seen her. I wouldn't say
exactly I've met her.
I don't know why I'm doing this.
By the way, I took your advice
and I'm pleased I did. Thank you.
Glad to be of service.
Rose?
Where did you get that?
I found it in the attic.
I got Alfred to bring it downstairs.
I'm so sorry but I...
I can't dance after all.
What was that about?
The gramophone.
It belonged to Matthew.
I didn't think.
What a pity.
Four nines.
You're too good for me.
He's too good for all of us.
Nonsense.
I've been lucky, that's all.
I'm wondering if I ought to stop.
I'm in pretty deep. I'm in deeper
I'm sad to say.
Your luck is about to change,
gentlemen. I'm certain of it.
If it doesn't,
how do you like to be paid?
Don't worry. I'm happy with IOUs.
We can settle up when we leave
or at the club.
Besides, you may have won
it all back by the end.
Not a chance.
I hope you can all keep my secret?
I wouldn't want to worry
Lady Grantham.
We must practise our poker face.
Antes, gentlemen.
Good night.
How are you enjoying the party?
(SIGHS) I look like a fool.
I talk like a fool. I am a fool.
Alfred said you were dancing.
With an old bat
who could be my granny
and thinks I grew up in a cave.
My clothes deceive no one.
Don't be so hard on yourself.
I'm a fish out of water and
I've never felt it more than today.
Good day, m'lord?
Good until tonight.
I took a walloping from Mr Sampson.
At poker.
I was a fool to play with someone
who so obviously knew what he was
doing.
Lord Gillingham tried to warn me
but I wouldn't listen.
Do you know the gentleman well?
No.
But I was discussing the party
at the club
and he hinted a bit
and I suppose I took the bait.
Anyway.
Perhaps keep it to yourself, Bates.
Of course, m'lord.
Good man.
(DOOR OPENS)
M'lady? What's the matter?
Did you know that Lady Rose
had found Mr Crawley's gramophone?
I did, yes.
She wanted it for her records.
I told her to ask you.
Well, she didn't.
I feel very sad tonight.
And no wonder.
She shouldn't have had it brought
down and set off your memories.
No, it's not that.
At least, it's not only that.
Sometimes I don't know
whom I'm most in mourning for.
Matthew or the person I used to be
when I was with him.
You're a fine person, m'lady.
Fine and strong. And you'll learn
that for yourself as time goes by.
I made rather an idiot of myself
in front of Lord Gillingham.
He won't mind.
No.
No, I don't think he will.
Can you stop a moment, please,
and let me out?
Isobel! Isobel, my dear.
Will you come up tonight
and hear Melba?
Well, I can't decide.
I... I have a lot to do.
Look, my dear,
I don't want to be unkind,
and you have my sympathy, truly.
But it won't bring him back for you
to sit alone night after night.
I know.
But you see, I have this feeling
that when I laugh
or read a book or hum a tune,
it means that I've forgotten him.
Just for a moment.
And it's that that I can't bear.
Better by far that you
should forget and smile,
than that you should remember
and be sad.
But Rosetti was writing about
her own death, not her child's.
Will you come?
I came
as soon as I got your message.
I hope I didn't drag you away
from anything important.
Oh, no, I've finished for the day.
At Bakewell's?
I am in a predicament.
James, the first footman, has
sprained his wrist and cannot carry.
Mr Barrow feels
the duties are beneath him,
and in the meantime, we have
a party of 16 staying at the house.
You want me to be a footman?
I know it is far below your talents
but you do understand the duties
and since you are working
at Bakewell's...
You mean I can fall no further.
I wondered if you might do us
the great favour of helping me out.
I have come down in the world,
Mr Carson. We both know that.
I am a beggar and so, as the proverb
tells us, I cannot be a chooser.
Hmm!
Do you know
if Dame Nellie has arrived?
I believe so, m'lady.
But too late for tea! What a shame.
I was getting nervous but
apparently Dame Nellie is here.
Good.
Are you enjoying yourself so far?
Seeing the house
at full strength again? I am.
At any rate,
I'm enjoying most of it. Only most?
I don't want Sampson invited back.
I think he's rather a tyke.
Hmm.
How do you find Mr Gregson?
Well, Sampson hammered him but he
took it like a man, I will say that.
I hope you weren't caught up in it?
I was more of a spectator.
I hate gambling.
How can grown men throw away their
fortune like that? What could be
more stupid?
I couldn't agree more.
Mr Molesley, I thought it was you!
Are you a footman now?
I'm having my career backwards.
Ah, Mr Molesley.
Alfred will be acting first footman
so can you take your lead from him?
Why not? Perhaps Daisy'd like to
give me a pointer or two. Or Ivy?
And here are some clean gloves
that should fit you.
Gloves, Mr Carson?
I'm sorry, Mr Molesley,
you're not the butler here.
That is my job. You are a footman
and a footman wears gloves.
So if we could begin?
Everyone ready? Go!
Hey! You're pushing! You can't just
bulldoze us all to one side!
It's all part of the rules.
I've got the ace!
(ALL SHOUT AND LAUGH)
Someone's cheating!
What on earth can she be doing?
Should someone go up and see?
I thought she was going to sing
after dinner. She is.
Then why
would we want to see her before?
I er... I suppose you'll get up
a game again tonight, after the
singing?
During it, with any luck.
Then you must count me in.
You'll play again?
If you'll have me.
I think
I've got the trick of it now.
Very well. If you insist.
Don't say I didn't warn you.
(LAUGHS)
Do you know Isabella Moncrieffe?
No.
She's blown up like a balloon!
She's in her room?
How long has she been there?
Her maid took her some tea
when she arrived... What?
I'm about to send up dinner.
Doesn't she want to eat with us?
I didn't think it appropriate,
ma'am, and his lordship agreed
with me.
I can't believe my ears.
Robert?
A world-famous singer
is in our house,
a great artist honoured by the King,
but you felt it beneath your dignity
to eat with her?
I don't recall... Am I the only
member of this family who lives in
the twentieth century?
What room is she in?
Princess Amelia, m'lady.
You will have her next to you
at dinner and you will like it!
But what do I say to her?
What does one say to a singer?
I blame you!
Now spoon it into the shells.
No, not like that!
Oh, give it here!
Mrs Patmore, we can do this.
Oh, can you? With Ivy slapping it
out like a trained seal.
Alfred, just remember that one's
for the Duchess. She can't eat...
Oh! Oh my God!
What is it?
I've got a pain like a vice!
It's like a vice!
Ivy, fetch Mrs Hughes!
Alfred, help me get her to a chair.
No but who'll finish the dinner?
I've not made the bechamel yet
nor the dill sauce for the salmon!
Daisy? But I've all my own stuff
to do. I'll do it.
Madge is ringing for the doctor.
What is going on?
Alfred's making the sauces and
Mrs Patmore's having a heart attack!
I'm not surprised!
No, I mean really!
(SHOUTING)
What on earth...
Don't ask.
Molesley? Oh, you're back?
I'm so glad.
They can't keep a good man down.
On the contrary, m'lady.
That's exactly what they can do.
I'm going to slip away later
for cards. I hope you won't mind.
Not with Sampson again?
You said you'd lost a packet.
Well...
Ah. It's time to turn.
I'm so sorry about earlier. I hope
you didn't feel we'd abandoned you.
This is delicious.
I'm so pleased you like it.
Haut-Brion.
It's one of my favourites.
Did you read that on the menu?
I didn't need to.
I've made quite a study of Claret.
Oh, well, then. This is going to be
much less uphill than I thought.
I'll ring tomorrow and make an
appointment. Tom can come with me.
I'm sure you don't need my help
but it's yours for the asking.
Thank you.
May I take you out for dinner,
when you're in London?
I don't think Miss Lane Fox
would approve
and nor would I, really.
But I can't tell you what a lift
it is to hear that you'd like to.
Really?
(LAUGHS)
Is something the matter?
If it is, it shouldn't be.
It's the first time I've
heard her laugh since it happened.
I know, and I don't want her
to spend her life in sorrow.
She's not the Lady of Shalott.
It's just I find it hard
to join in the merry-making.
We haven't all been making merry.
What it comes down to in the end
is this nice Lord Gillingham,
and Sir John over there,
and him and him and you,
you're all alive.
My son's dead.
(SHOUTING AND LAUGHTER)
Anna.
Anna!
ANNA!
Are you so involved in your game
you were unaware Mrs Patmore has
been taken ill?
What? What sort of ill?
Ill enough to make this racket
inappropriate.
Well, I was going to win.
Yes, I think you were.
Which is a good omen.
What for?
Never you mind. (GIGGLES)
Why are you being like this?
I was just having fun.
I'll leave you to it.
Please do.
Thank you for organising that,
Mr Gillingham. It was terrific.
(KNOCK)
How is she?
She'll live.
I think it was brought on by panic
over all the things that had to be
done.
There was a lot to be done. But
you mustn't let it overpower you.
Can I listen to Dame Nellie?
I think so.
But put your feet up
when they've left in the morning.
You should stay for the concert.
I don't want to be a nuisance
but it does seem too good to miss.
I'll go and put my bag in the car.
I don't know,
screaming in the servants' hall,
singers chatting to his lordship
and a footman cooking the dinner.
What a topsy-turvy world
we've come to.
I needed something to get me
through it and I see you've had the
same idea.
Are you all right?
No. I'm afraid I've let you down.
What? Why?
Since Sybil died you allowed me
to believe I was one of you.
You are one of us. Now.
No, I'm not. Not when you're among
your own people.
Tom, something's upset you.
Was it the Duchess?
If so, I wouldn't pay
the slightest attention.
It wasn't her fault.
She was only trying to be nice.
It was me.
I don't belong here and these
past few days have shown me that.
I don't accept what you're saying
and Cora certainly won't.
But we must go now
or we'll get stick.
Do any of you ever leave school?
♪ Seldom from
♪ Her eyelids
♪ Where the teardrops
♪ Banished
I'm sneaking off.
I wish I knew why.
You will.
♪ Now I teach
♪ My children
I hope I didn't let you down.
I'm sure you didn't.
Mr Carson said
they gobbled it up like gannets.
That's what I want to do,
Mrs Patmore.
One step at a time.
♪ Are flowing
♪ Oft they flow
I've got a bit of a headache.
Because of the singing?
Well,
it's not making it any better.
Probably all that shouting
in the game.
And I'll thank you not to comment.
I'll pop down and get something.
(SONG ENDS)
And now for one of my favourites.
O Mio Babbino Caro
by Puccini from Gianni Schicchi.
And I'd like to dedicate
this to love and to lovers.
What a relief.
I thought we might have been in for
some of that dreadful German lieder.
You can always rely on Puccini.
I prefer Bartok.
Oh, you would.
(SINGS IN ITALIAN)
Straight to the six.
Flush.
I don't understand how...
How what?
Sampson, you're not trying
to get out of paying up, are you?
Of course not.
Care for something stronger?
I shouldn't let Mr Carson
see you with that.
You want some?
I expect you're sick of it too.
A grown woman
screeching like a cat on a bonfire.
(LAUGHS)
That's very naughty. I think Dame
Nellie has a beautiful voice.
Don't be silly. Let me pass.
You look to me like you could
use a bit of real fun for once.
Is that what you want?
What I want is to go back upstairs.
You're not telling me that
sad old cripple keeps you happy?
If you must know,
yes, he keeps me very happy.
Now let me by. Please.
Perhaps you've forgotten
what you're missing.
Argh!
(OPERA SINGING CONTINUES)
(ANNA SCREAMS)
(SINGING CONTINUES)
(DOOR OPENS)
I wonder what she's doing.
Maybe she's fallen asleep.
Well, she wouldn't get much sleep
up here, that's for sure.
(SONG ENDS)
I think we're both even.
So we'll leave you to it.
I assume you'll take an IOU?
Firstly I'll take all the IOUs
you've accumulated during your stay.
You may send me a cheque
for the rest.
I'm not sure I can allow that.
Or I'll tell Lord Grantham
how you won
and there won't be a club in London
to touch you with a ten foot pole.
Will you take a note
for the remainder of the debt? Yes.
It wouldn't be in your interest
to cross me.
You think you're so holy, don't you?
You're just a cheat, like me.
I have won against a card sharp.
There is pleasure in that.
I'm so pleased you came.
So am I.
I was wrong to hesitate but then
guilt has the power to make all of
us do strange things.
Oh! Well not all of us.
Guilt has never played
a major part in my life.
Amen to that.
I think these are yours.
Oh, I can't accept this.
Please do.
I won it off Sampson
fair and square.
Fair and square, eh?
Well, I won, anyway.
But the money's yours.
I don't want it.
Isn't that a better way
to end the house party?
(LAUGHS)
How did it go?
Mr Gregson has saved my bacon.
But don't tell your mother.
How on earth did you do that?
I revived a dubious talent
from my misspent youth.
Well, that was a nice surprise,
I must say.
My whole stay has been full
of nice surprises.
I can't tell you how pleased I am
that I came. Really?
Then I'm pleased too.
What is it?
Whisky.
God, it's huge.
I thought you might need it.
You understand me, don't you?
I like to think so.
Some fresh coffee, Mr Molesley.
Shut the door.
My God!
Shut the door!
Will you help me?
Will you find me some clothes?
Of course I will but...
Will you see to Lady Mary?
Say erm... Just say
I've gone home with a headache.
I can manage Lady Mary
but Anna, we must tell someone...
No, no, no!
But you'll have to tell Mr Bates...
Him least of all! He'd murder the
man who's done it and then he'd be
hanged.
But surely...
He's a convicted felon!
Do you think they'd spare him
a second time? No.
Maybe the doctor's still here.
Will you listen!
I need your help
or I wouldn't have told you.
Nobody else must ever know.
You promise me!
Wait here.
I'll fetch you some water
and a comb.
And see what I can find you
in the way of a dress.
(CRIES)
Did you enjoy your evening?
Yes, I did rather.
You weren't too shocked, having
to talk to a professional singer?
You always make me out to be
so narrow minded but I liked her.
Because she appreciated your wine?
There are worse reasons.
And have you formed
an opinion of Mr Gregson?
Yes, as a matter of fact.
I'm not sure
he's what we want for Edith
but it's a changing world and I must
admit, he's a decent cove.
Heavens! A Damascene conversion.
What's brought this about?
Was it something he said?
It wasn't that so much.
But he did behave in a way
that I thought was really quite
gentlemanly.
Are you awake?
What happened to you?
I was drinking a powder
when I suddenly felt dizzy and I...
I must have fainted. I think I hit
the edge of the sink as I went down.
Stupid.
You've changed your dress.
Yes. It's badly marked.
I've put it in to soak
but I'm not sure I can save it.
Mrs Hughes lent me this.
Good night, Mr Bates. Mrs Bates.
And thank you for looking after me
while I've been here.
Good night, Mr Gillingham.
What's the matter?
Nothing.
I just feel like walking on my own.
That's all.
BATES: Anna!
I blush to admit it
but I was very drunk.
So you're not going to deny it?
If I behaved badly, I am sorry.
Sorry to keep you waiting but Anna
couldn't find... Oh! I hope I'm a
surprise and not a shock.
I could take you all
to hear the new band at the club.
But tonight you've made me
play truant. And I like it.
Jack Ross at your service.
I'm Rose MacClare. How do you do?
You're trusting this man
with your name and your reputation.
Michael, I...
Oh, my darling.
We live together, we work together.
Sometimes I think it's just too
much.